Sois
Be!
Le feu et la terre
Fire and earth,
L'eau et la poussière
Water and dust,
Héros malgré toi
Unwilling hero...
Vois
See!
La légende s'écrire
The legend write itself,
L'histoire se construire
History build itself,
L'avenir est notre aventure
The future is our adventure.
Fais
Make!
Vivre la lumière
The light live,
Parler les éclairs
Lightnings talk,
La magie entre tes mains
The magic in your hands.
Pars
Go!
Suive ton chemin
Follow your path,
Et regarde ton futur
And watch your future,
L'aventure
Adventure,
Ta lumière guider ton destin
Light guiding your destiny!
15-Wabbit Island
Eh, Ruel, what're you doing in that clam?
Don't worry, little Junior, I'll get him out of there.
Help me, Yugo! Grab the other foot!
Uhh... I really don't feel like doing that right after waking up.
Ah! If I get my hands on the fair-weather sailor that dared throw us overboard while I was sleeping,
I don't know what I'll...
And if you hadn't vomited all over his boat,
we'd have already arrived in the Crimson Claws Archipelago. Iop-brain.
Where's Eva?
A bit further in the jungle.
Did you find something, Eva?
Yes, this statue, there are more all over.
All indications are that we're on Wabbit Island.
Wabbit Island?
So that's a wabbit?
No, that's a lenald.
Really?!
So why isn't it called Lenald Island?
The lenalds were the first inhabitants of the island, Yugo.
But they were massacred when the wabbits came.
That's right I remember now! There's a great dungeon here, with a great boss,
the Wa Wabbit! Can we go, can we go?
We've got a quest to finish, Grovy, we're not here to have fun.
Come on, Eva, just a little boss.
Come on, say yes, say yes, say yes...
I said no! No boss, no dungeon, no fighting!!
Anyway, you never let us do anything fun.
If that's how it is, I'll sulk!
And how do you plan on leaving?
By swimming?
I've got an idea!
We'll go to the dungeon, thrash the big wodent, and force him to give us a boat.
They are wabbits, Grovy, not wodents.
And wabbits, they're more diggers than sailors.
I'll remind you that we're on an island, Ruel, and where there's an "island", there's a "boat".
And why would they want to dig on an island to begin with, huh?
Feels like we'we going to have some fun.
A cwaft, I have a cwaft. Help me and you can bowwow it.
I'm the Wa Wabbit.
I... I was... I was banished.
You were banished?
Yes! Shamefully banished. I am the king of this island, the Wa Wabbit.
The Wa Wabbit, the great boss!
Wow, this rocks! The one who banished you, he's gotta be super strong then.
Help me, and I'll give you a... a... a cwaft.
That's funny, I feel like I've already been through this before.
Yes, except the other time it was a pig.
Oh, right. Here.
No thanks, I am a vegetawian.
Really? So you're not a wabbit?
Mowon!
Vegetawian, it means that he doesn't eat meat or fish.
So what does he eat, then?
Cawwots of couwse.
Well, if you'd please tell us what happened to you?
Well, I was at home peacefully doing a little puzzle,
and some cwoss-stiching.
What-stitching?
You got it pewfectly.
Good, let's get to the facts. We won't spend the night here.
I was getting to that.
I was attacked by a demonic monstew, capable of casting evil spells and black magic.
We dug ouw buwwows too deep, and we awakened an evil that had been sleeping since ancient times.
I did what I could, but he was too stwong.
All I could do was flee and abandon my people.
Don't cry, wodent!
I didn't understand everything that you said, but me and my group are going to help you recapture your dungeon.
Unfortunately, we have to get off the island as soon as possible and we can't help you.
I see, but how will you get off the island without my cwaft?
He's got a point.
Um, excuse us for a second, we have to consult each other.
Go ahead, but quickly. The island is full of mowons...
Err... I mean, full of jolly hewoes who would be glad to help me.
So? Isn't that great? He's a real boss, a legendary boss.
We have to put him back where he belongs in his dungeon,
otherwise, it will be the end of the dream for millions of adventurers.
What do you think about him?
I don't really trust him.
Yes, but how are we going to get off the island without his boat?
And he's a king too.
Helping him could be worth it.
Also, this mysterious hooded enemy worries me.
If he's as dangerous as the Wa Wabbit says, we'll have to stop him.
In a way, it's our duty as heroes, right?
Okay, we're going to help you get your throne back, in exchange for your promise that you'll give us your boat.
It's a pwomise, cwoss my heawt.
Yuck!
Is this the entrance to the famous wabbit dungeon?
No, it's ONE OF the entwances.
Let it go, they're amateurs.
Well, shall we go? I'm itching for a fight.
Ah! By Sadida, what a terrible stench. What if we changed our minds in the end?
Indeed, it doesn't really make me want to go down there...
AZ!!!
Well now we have to go get him, don't we?
Az!
Az? Az, are you okay?
What's the matter with you?!
That's a technique to avoid fiwedamp explosions.
You don't know it?
Of course I do! All Enutrofs know about firedamps.
It's a pocket of gas that forms in galleries, and can explode with just the slightest spark.
So we have tofus go in first. If they choke, that means there's gas.
What!? "If they choke"?
And do these firedamp explosions happen often? Err, I mean, fiwedamp.
Well I don't know, I'm not the one digging. Aftewwawds your fingews stink all ovew...
Am I dreaming!? You let your subjects dig, risk blowing up, all while you're doing puzzles?
Well yeah! Isn't that what kings do in youw countwy?
Well, he's got a point.
Well, peoples' rights and all that is an interesting subject, but we have to advance.
Well said, Eva. Then let's go!
So, do we start over there... or over here?
Oh, you wewe asking me?
Well I don't know.
What do you mean, you don't know? You don't know whewe you live anymowe?
Of couwse I know whewe I live.
This is my whabbitat anyway.
But I had an awchitect build it. What did you expect? I delegate.
I'm a modewn monawch, you know.
More like a real tywant.
Anyway! As for me, I'm heading that way.
Since Grovy is holding the cawwot, all we have to do is follow.
Actually, Grovy, wabbits replace the letter "R" with the letter "W". For example, "Wuel", that means "Ruel".
Ah, I see. Let me try, but start with an easy one, okay?
Iop-bwain. Huh, so what does that one mean? C'mon, what does it mean?
Oh no, I can't figure it out. Foreign languages are really hard anyway, you know, Ruel.
Right...
We'we almost thewe.
Nowmally, my thwone woom should be just behind this doow.
See, it's already over. We were right to trust him.
Whewe did we fall to?
Into a dawk hole.
We shouldn't stay here!
I lost some Kamas!
Get going, we have to hurry, the level's rising.
We'we in the sowting woom. Hewe is whewe we thwow wotten cawwots.
Yugo, your turn!
What do we do now?
Good question. For now, I'd say this dungeon is pretty easy to break out of.
Grovy, you're a genius. Amalia, your doll.
Ah! Still more arachnees, I'll take care of them!
What now, Grovy?
Now? We rush!
After you.
But above all pay attention, there are traps everywhere.
Let me handle it, I'll take care of everything.
Ah, why am I not surprised?
Junior, fetch the nuggets for daddy.
Ah, that's my good little Junior.
Look! The collapse revealed the exit.
A labyrinth! That's the last straw.
Too easy!
We just have to split up and the first one to find the exit will call the others.
No wait!
What a mowon! Grovy, come back.
Hey, where are you guys?
Over here!
No, over here!
I'm here!
I found it. Oh! You're already here?
Hold me back or I'll turn him into cawwot puree!
- Come on, let's rush!
Ah, we can't mess up here.
We have to take the correct door, otherwise we'll have to start all over again from the beginning.
But it's obviously the one on the right!
No, Eva, things aren't that simple.
Stop acting like a Iop-head.
And you, stop correcting me every time I--
Settle down, lovebiwds. I know a vewy good method to get you two to agwee.
We're going to follow my path because I'm the only real dungeon expert.
If I wasn't here to watch over you, you'd still be one of Rubilax's home decorations.
Let me remind you that Rubilax is the one who saved me first. And it's also thanks to him that I saved your life.
"Saved my life"? That's the least you could have done after breaking my bow!
What of it? If I hadn't broken your old bow, you wouldn't have gotten a new super powerful one.
I'm weally pwoud of them. They wowked hawd. All of these twaps awe weally well made.
Uh, instead of preening yourself, look for a way to get us out of here, or we're going to be put through the mill.
I know, I know. We have to do a stupid dance while following the arrows on the ground in order to open the door.
Whewe do you get these stupid ideas?
Well, uh... I know some people who've done it...
Look here, there's an inscription.
"What is invisible and smells like a cawwot?"
I know, it's a fart.
Of course not...
Yes it is, Grovy's right. But we all have to say it like a wabbit.
All together now...
Fawt!
That wasn't the correct answer.
What do we do now?
It's too late!
We'we all gonna die!
Your riddles aren't even worth a wabbit's fawt!
Thanks fow evewything. I'll take cawe of the west.
Wow! A lenald. I thought they had all disappeared.
Yes. Me too...
Guawds!
Wemove these gawlands, and put those guys in pwison.
I knew we shouldn't have trusted him.
Hey! Dirty liar, you promised us a boat!
He's even a real meanie who doesn't keep his word.
So classy!
You don't have the light to implison me, I won this loyal dungeon fail and squale.
Sule, since we no longel have an island, we do what we can to sulvive.
As fol me, my specialty is calds. I'm a gleat pokel playel.
It's vely lale fol a lenald, that's fol sule.
What'd he say?
He said that he was a gweat pokew playew and that's wawe fow a wenawd.
Twy to keep up a bit.
Anyway, that day...
I was at home, playing calds.
When suddenly...
I was not going to leave without tlying one last game of pokel.
What about a little game of calds?
I win!
I win again!
Things come in thlees. Now scat, get outta hele!
So, this dungeon and evelything in it is mine.
Endangewed species have nothing to weclaim. Guawds! Send evewyone to the dungeon!
You lost your dungeon in a game of cards?! But a dungeon boss is supposed to fight, and slice, and smash!
Do you really want to shatter the dream of thousands of adventurers?
Wasn't it millions just this morning?
You know, Grovy and numbers. After "two", he always loses count.
So, if that's how it is, then it's you and me, no cards! And the winner gets the dungeon!
Hey! Wait, this dungeon is mine!
Okay, I'll offew you the fight of youw dweams, Iop.
Grovy, catch the Wa, we'll take care of these two here.
Come and fight me!
Ah, finally...
What was THAT ?
Unless I'm mistaken, a WaWabehameha.
A Ma-be-wa-whu-what?
Watch out, moron!
Thanks, giwl. Watch out!
No more running, wodent!
Good, there shouldn't be that many dungeons left to finish.
Wodents are too easy.
Hey! What do you think you're doing?
Oh, solly. I just wanted to bling it to you.
I like that better
Okay! You've had your toy. Can we leave now?
What? But who's gonna look after my dungeon if I leave?
That's wight, especially now that you have a lot to do.
We must summon the awchitects, consolidate gallewies, find a bettew hiding place fow the Cawwot Dofus.
We'll also have to get wid of a plague of gewbils on the thiwd sub-floow.
Oh, and the Wobots Union would like to have a wowd with you.
Oh, well... okay.
To each his own, huh?
I kind of have a "grand" quest to accomplish, so I'll leave the dungeon to you.
Wait a minute, you still owe us a boat.
I nevew spoke of a boat.
I pwomised you a cwaft. It's diffewent.
Oh, so this is a "cwaft"?
Well it's kind of like a boat, but smaller.
I have a feeling we got wobbed.
Let's just hope that it doesn't take on water.
Watew? Don't wowwy about that.
Howevew, you will have plenty of aiw.
What do you mean by that?
Just look up thewe.
Sayonawa!
Lenald people!
I have a dleam!
A gleam?
No! I have a leal hope.
A lil' soap?