Sois
Be!
Le feu et la terre
Fire and earth,
L'eau et la poussière
Water and dust,
Héros malgré toi
Unwilling hero...
Vois
See!
La légende s'écrire
The legend write itself,
L'histoire se construire
History build itself,
L'avenir est notre aventure
The future is our adventure.
Fais
Make!
Vivre la lumière
The light live,
Parler les éclairs
Lightnings talk,
La magie entre tes mains
The magic in your hands.
Pars
Go!
Suive ton chemin
Follow your path,
Et regarde ton futur
And watch your future,
L'aventure
Adventure,
Ta lumière guider ton destin
Light guiding your destiny!
16~The Cursed Fountain
Thirsty... So thirsty...
Could someone explain to me why we always end up in such situations?
Because we spend our time taking tours and detours.
When we're not busy being tourists, we're saving the weak and the helpless.
Yeah, but we're heroes. And a hero has a duty to help others.
I'm with Grovy, a hero is there to make the world a nicer place.
I agree as well. But there are tragic stories and people to save on every street corner.
We have to know what we want, what's our priority?
I don't know... I don't know anymore... My brain is fried.
Yugo, answer me!
Our priority?
Well, to find Shinonome's Dofus.
Well it doesn't look like it.
It's been weeks since we left, and we're not even halfway there.
At this rate, it's going to take months.
Have you thought about Adamaï?
You promised him that we'd be back as quickly as possible.
Each one of us has put their heart into your quest, Yugo.
So if you wish to fight the world's misery, so be it!
But if you don't mind, we'll do that after we're done with this mission.
I-I...
I understand, Eva. From now on, we'll focus on our quest.
Look over there!
It's the oasis that the map mentioned!
Drink!
Over there! I can hear running water!
Yeah, over there, there's an entrance.
Hey! Wait for me guys!
That's it, we're dead. This is paradise.
Grovy, it hurts me to admit it, but you've summed it all up.
Water!!
Get back, strangers.
My name is Bordegann, and I won't let anybody drink this fountain's water.
Oh yeah?
And why can't we drink?
Have pity my lord, we are in dire need of refreshment.
It's true that it's rather hot in here.
But I'm sorry, you can't drink this water.
Don't think I'll drink to that.
Excuse me sir, but why can't we drink from it?
Why can't you drink from it? Well...
Well...
because you must not drink from it!
Hey! That's a pretty short argument you have there, kid!
Yeah! I'm with my buddy Ruel on this.
No!
Huh?
Stop, I beg of you.
Forgive him, he's not a bad person.
It's just that... he doesn't know what he's doing anymore.
I have some water.
Here, drink it all if you want.
Hey, thanks, Miss.
Women and children first!
Get back, stranger. My name is Bordegann and I protect--
I know, Bordegann, I know. I'm not interested in the fountain.
I'm just bringing you something to eat.
Something to eat?
How thoughtful. Thanks, miss.
Today I have some dried fruits, cereals, and for dessert: a calouga.
Wow, how nice, that's my favorite dessert. How did you guess?
Because I come here every day, Bordegann.
Really? And... and what's your name?
Alia...
My name is Alia.
Alia? That's a pretty name.
Well, thanks a lot, Alia.
See you tomorrow, Bordegann...
If you'd please follow me,
my village isn't far from here. Allow me to offer you a bit of hospitality.
The village's fountain is... right there.
We don't see many strangers around here. Stay a while, I'd be glad to get news from the world.
It would be a pleasure, but we still have a long journey ahead.
We'd better not linger.
At least take a bit of food, the road to the south coast is tough.
In order to cross this desert, you'll need sufficient provisions.
Okay! That's very kind of you.
Amy, I'm going with Yugo. Go get the others.
We'll meet here.
Hey! You're not supposed to hit old people!
My name is Bordegann, I guard this fountain, and you won't get near it!
Listen kiddo. I pity you, so I'll spare you.
You're really asking for that spanking!
Enough!
Just stop already!
Forgive him, strangers, he has no manners.
If you want to eat or drink, there's Louca's Inn. I was just going there.
Get back home right now, before I get angry!
What kind of manners are those?! Now, off with you!
I think we've stumbled upon a village of lunatics.
I'll also add a bit of dried meat, as a side dish.
Why is Bordegann guarding the fountain? What's so special about it?
It's cursed.
Cursed?
It's a long and sad story.
Bordegann is my love.
We all came from another island that was engulfed by the rise of waters from Ogrest's Chaos.
Bordegann had heard of an abandoned village.
Conditions would be harsh, the place would be isolated from everything,
but what mattered most was that we would have a new home.
Bordegann was the one leading the first expedition tasked with locating the place and restoring the village.
But after two weeks without any news, we decided to go looking for them.
The inhabitants had all disappeared, and Bordegann was the only one left...
There, near that cursed fountain.
He had gone half crazy.
He had lost his memory and didn't recognize me anymore.
I don't know what happened, but I refuse to believe that it's my love's fault.
The fountain's the one to blame. Bordegann is just trying to protect us from it, I'm certain of it.
Ever since, I've been taking care of him, I bring him food every day, hoping he'll recover his memory.
The villagers think that I'm crazy, that there's no hope, but I'll wait as long as needed.
I... I can't abandon him.
There must be a way to restore his mind... We'll help you!
Yugo...
Yes, Eva.
I...
I'm sorry Alia. We have an urgent quest to carry out.
But we'll come back to help you, I promise.
Won't we, Eva?
Alia's very pretty, but she's kind of bird-brained, if you ask me.
As for me, such a boor as Bordegann wouldn't be enough to keep me around.
I would've run off long ago to see if the grass was greener elsewhere.
What were they thinking, burrowing in such a godforsaken place?
Even their kids have gone nuts.
Well, I do understand her. Love can sometimes turn you completely Iop.
Right, Eva?
No, I can't!
What? You can't walk? Do you want me to carry you?
No, I can't... I don't want to leave them like that. We've got to go back.
What's she talking about?
Go back? But why? Did you forget something?
Thanks, Eva.
Can someone explain to me what's going on?
I suppose you have done some research...
Yes, but we didn't find anything. Only Bordegann is left.
The villagers that accompanied him disappeared without a trace.
That cursed fountain's the one to blame, that's for sure.
But as I told you, we don't know if it's the water or the place that's cursed.
Well then we're going to study it stone by stone, there's bound to be a clue.
What kind of clue are we looking for?
Anything that looks magical. A gemstone, runes, a stele.
You're forgetting something...
Bordegann.
He won't let you get near the fountain.
Yeah. We've already tried several times, we never succeeded.
They're right. Bordegann is too strong. It's a lost cause.
Well it just so happens that we're specialists in lost causes.
Yeah! That's even how you recognize heroes.
Get back, stranger! My name is Bordegann and I protect--
I know, Bordegann, I know, I'm not interested in the fountain, I'm just bringing you something to eat.
Something to eat?
...and your favorite dessert: a calouga.
A calouga!
Are you ready?
Yeah! Ready to fight!
Grovy! The point is not to fight him, but to immobilize him and find some clues.
Oh, come on, I was just kidding.
Here we go!
What?!
What in the...
Your turn, guys!
We've got to check every nook and cranny.
What?!
What in the...
I'm really sorry, Bordegann.
No! The fountain! You must not get near it!
Villains! You will taste my wrath!
He's a tough one, that's for sure.
Say, Eva. Couldn't I use my sword? Just a little bit, to see if...
Grovy, no!
Well, at least tomorrow he'll have forgotten everything.
Well, we'll try something else.
Marriage?
Yes, our marriage.
Come on, hurry up, the mayor is waiting for us.
Yes, miss! Err... Alia!
One moment, I'm going to find my spear.
Uh, haven't I forgotten something? Now what was it again?
Come on, Bordegann! We're going to be late!
Oh yeah!
Get back, stranger, nobody must get near this fountain!
Well, Grovy, what was your plan again?
Oh! A calouga!
This is how my master got me out of a well that I had hidden in to sulk.
He's biting! He's biting, come help!
It's a big one, a real big one!
All together!
Well, Yugo, what was your idea again?
...and your favorite dessert: a calouga!
My favorite? Really? But... but how do you know that?
Oh it's a very long story, but I can tell you about it, if you wish.
With pleasure, stranger. I love stories.
At least... I-I think I do.
Ruel can talk for whole days without stopping.
A treasure like you've never seen!
Kamas by the hundreds, by the thousands! Ha, I believed I was in Enutrof's heaven.
Alas, yeah, alas...
...managed to steal from me. Such boldness!
Luckily, they were lead by a boss as ugly and stupid as my great-grandfather.
I say luckily, because, this time,
I had skimped a bit on the costs, and my steed wasn't of the highest grade.
Anyway, had it been a matter of speed...
...So I said to him: "Do you take me for a bank or what?"
"This shovel isn't even worth the earth that soils it!"
"You think you can scam me, kiddo, but I wouldn't put Kamas on it."
With a man of my rank... it was a bold move. And in such cases, there's only one solution: you don't let go of anything!
I look him straight in the eyes and I say to him: "See, in this world there's two kinds of people, my friend:
those who pay, and those who get paid!"
Hey! Hey!
"You pay!"
Hands off my Eva!
Who are you? What are you doing in my room?
We told you so: not gonna work. We've already tried everything to get him out of there.
Yeah... Hope is just an illusion. And we stopped having illusions long ago.
By the way, what are these critters?
We don't know. They were here when we arrived.
If they could talk, they could tell us what really happened.
They're really funny.
Yes...
Without them, I think I would've lost all hope.
You're right! There's always hope.
We'll start over again from the beginning. Here's what we're gonna do...
What's your name, stranger?
Alia, my name is--
Help! Somebody!
Oh no! Someone's being attacked! Quick! Let's go check!
I'll handle him. Take care of the fountain!
Bubulle!
That's Bubulle, one of the villagers that disappeared!
Huh? What happened? Did anyone see anything?
The gemstones, at the bottom of the fountain, take them all out of the water, quickly!
It's working!
I've... understood... your... intentions... it's... the fountain... you're after!
No, you must not get near the fountain!
What the...
The water serpent, I remember it. We're doomed!
Bordegann, no!
Yugo!
You have to strike the fountain! Now! With full power!
It's too beautiful!
I don't remember a thing.
It's as if I was asleep all this time.
I... I don't know how to thank you.
Seeing you two reunited is enough.
You reminded me of what it means to be a "hero".
You know you're pretty nice as a zeroine.
Heroes are there to make the world a nicer place, aren't they?